Let me first introduce the new features of Marvelous Designer 11.
First of all, in Marvelous Designer 11,
the first new feature is the user interface change.
In Marvelous Designer 11,
in order to help you use Marvelous Designer more freely,
we have made some changes to the interface layout,
for example, you can arrange your own combinations.
On the left side of the user interface,
there are two windows.
The first one is the general window,
which is our working area.
If you have any questions,
you can send us a chat.
Jimmy is also here today.
He will answer your questions in a chat.
If you have any other questions,
you can ask them in the Q&A section,
because we are a bit busy today.
In addition to the usual working area window,
there is a store at the bottom.
In Marvelous Designer 11,
the store has been integrated into the app,
which is the software.
So you don't need to go to the official website to buy.
Let's go back to the main interface.
In Marvelous Designer 11,
we mainly divide the main interface into
the working area window and the side window.
These are the side windows that can be arranged randomly.
For the main window,
click on the top triangle to change its type.
In the past, there was a model window in the upper right corner.
In the latest Marvelous Designer version,
we have adopted such a setting.
Click on the title name at the top,
you can change its type.
For example,
I can change the 2D window to a UV editor.
I can also open two 3D windows at the same time.
In addition,
you can see that there is a side window on the side.
The side window can also be switched to a mode.
For example,
I can change the material window to a button.
In Marvelous Designer 11,
we can duplicate all these windows,
and arrange them freely,
or arrange them in different positions.
So when I duplicate a window,
this window will be arranged freely in the form of a button.
Then,
this window,
when I pop it out,
drag it to the top or bottom of the other pop-out windows,
it will automatically arrange them.
After I put it in,
we can choose to fold these windows.
Click on the label next to it again,
you can directly cancel the folding of these windows.
Click on the big X in the upper right corner,
you can close this window.
Click on the big X in the upper right corner, you can close this window.
Click on the big X in the upper right corner,
you can open this window.
If we duplicate a side window,
a free-use side window like this,
we can drag this side window
and place it into the window of the other pop-out window.
So, they form a group.
For example,
I turn its type into a button.
So, we can click on the label below
to switch these two windows.
Now they form a group.
If you,
For example, if you want to close the tree window, you can do the same by clicking on the big X in the upper right corner.
After talking about the secondary window, let's take a look at the main window.
In Marvelous Designer 11, the main window can be opened in multiple ways.
In the previous version of Marvelous Designer, there is only one 3D window and only one 2D window.
For some users who use multiple screens, it may be a little too large.
After that, we can click on the switch in the lower right corner.
For example, there are two windows, that is, we have one 3D window and one 2D window that we use most often.
If we click on three windows, our screen will be divided into two.
There will be a 3D window here and two windows here.
For these two windows, we can look at the 3D window from different angles.
Or we can look at a UV editor or something else.
One thing worth noting is that there is only one 2D window at the same time.
So if you change the other windows to 2D windows, they will be exchanged.
OK.
For example, if I drag the 3D window into any other 3D window,
the other window will be able to see the side effects.
And the 3D window, as long as you select a 3D window, it will be linked to the 2D window.
Then we can think that we can open up to four work areas windows.
Then we can separate these windows.
Then we can separate these windows and put them on another screen.
In addition, if you need to open another window, you can display it here.
There is a window below.
There are some other options here.
For example, you can open a 3D window independently.
Because I have two screens, I have to drag it over.
For the users of three screens, it is also possible.
You can, but its size is relatively small.
OK.
Then when we have an independent 3D window, we can put it next to it.
It won't affect much if you look at multiple windows to simulate.
OK.
In addition to these, when you just looked at my main menu,
did you see?
There is a small scissors mark here.
What about the small scissors mark?
You click on it.
We can cut this window out.
In this way, some of the tools we often use can also be done separately.
It is more convenient to select these tools on the menu.
Including the windows of 3D and 2D.
As long as they have a download menu.
For example, we have this tool group of the edit version.
This tool group of the edit version.
When you select this tool group, click on this small scissors.
You can separate it into a single window.
You can put it in other places again.
So you can quickly select these functions.
OK.
In addition to these, you can also do this yourself.
You can adjust the tool bar of this work area.
For example, like the tool bar of 2D.
You can drag it to the left.
When the mouse becomes this.
When you drag this button.
You can drag it to the top.
Or drag it to the side.
Or drag it to the bottom.
Here.
For some people who are more used to some tools.
They are friends who count them.
You can drag it to the top.
OK.
In addition to this.
You can press this tool.
Fold 2D.
Tool bar.
Or fold 3D tool bar.
OK.
This is our.
Some changes about user interface.
Change.
And then.
There is one more thing.
It's not that everyone.
Is saying.
This is the latest version.
Many friends ask.
Where did the animation editor go?
In fact.
The animation editor is here.
It was hidden at the bottom.
OK.
Since we are talking about the animation editor.
Let's take a look.
Some changes to the animation editor.
If you are not used to the current user interface.
You can use Marvelous Designer 11 more.
This.
Because it's all about getting used to it.
The process.
And then.
Let's look at the animation editor.
In Marvelous Designer 11.
First of all.
We can see the animation editor.
Its tool bar.
Has been moved to the left.
Like this.
Here.
It's some of our usual tools.
Including.
Recording.
Video.
Recording animation.
This tool.
And then.
It's.
Next to it.
There will be.
Some of our play tools.
These are all of our usual.
For example.
Go back to the first frame.
Or go back to the last frame.
And then.
This is repeated.
You can replay the animation.
And then.
There is a simulation quality next to it.
That simulation quality.
In fact.
It corresponds to.
We are in the process of recording animation.
This.
The quality of the simulation.
If you choose to complete the animation.
Then.
The quality of your simulation.
Is more precise.
More stable.
And.
It will occupy you.
A computer.
Bigger.
A memory.
Or.
CPU.
It will stand.
Higher.
In this case.
You record an animation.
The time it takes.
Will be longer.
But.
The effect.
Will be better.
There is also.
Another thing.
That.
Is.
Normal speed.
What we usually use.
A simulation preset.
Then.
Use this.
The advantage of using this setting.
Is.
You.
The process of recording animation.
Will be very fast.
But.
It is not necessarily.
So stable.
You can.
Change it according to your needs.
If.
You.
Want.
My simulation.
To be a little bit stable.
But.
He doesn't want.
The recording time.
Too long.
Then.
You can.
Adjust.
A little bit.
But.
Don't.
Adjust.
To five.
Five.
Is.
The animation we just talked about.
Complete.
This setting.
Then.
You can.
Change it here.
To.
About.
Three.
That's it.
So.
It won't.
Record for too long.
Then.
The simulation.
Is.
More stable.
Then.
Next.
Is.
Our.
When.
We.
See.
The.
This.
Sensor.
I don't.
Need.
To.
Change.
The.
Sensor.
To.
Change.
The.
Sensor.
To.
Change.
Reset.
The.
Sensor.
So.
This.
Is.
For example, you want to increase the frame rate from 30 to 60, and you want all the frames, for example, the first frame is still in the first frame, and the 30th frame is still in the 30th frame, then you have to choose this one, keep the key frame in the current frame.
So when we change the frame rate, although our frame rate changes, the animation of each frame is still set above the current frame.
The next change here is what we have just mentioned, for example, the simulation quality, animation, default, and default.
There is also a format type below, true or false.
What does true or false mean?
True or false.
True or false means that these two options actually only affect the effect that you play, that is, the effect that you see with your naked eye, but it does not affect the input or output.
It is an effect when you preview.
So if you choose true or false, then this animation is to play a real number with the file you input.
In real time, there is no other factor that affects it.
It is purely that if your animation is 8 seconds, it will be finished in 8 seconds.
This is the setting.
Then the following are the starting and ending frames.
The starting frame is the first frame of the area you play.
For example, this is the 0th frame.
Then the ending area is, for example, like mine, which is 198 frames.
Then the scene time change.
The scene time change is a setting that we often use when we record animation.
The higher the scene time change, the slower it will simulate the action.
For example, it was originally a 5-second action.
If you increase the scene time change to 5 times, it will only finish the entire animation in 25 seconds.
The advantage of doing this is that,
although the animation has been simulated for a long time,
the number of frames it mimicked has increased.
So it will make you too slow.
It can also help our skirt, or some softer fabrics, to simulate more stable.
Then the following is our unit.
On the right side, there is a quick menu.
We just used these settings.
You can continue to make other settings on the right side.
I used HANA for this model.
After talking about these settings,
let's take a look at our panel.
On the panel of the animation editor,
first of all, you can see that we have supported the animation with a negative number.
Next, we can see that we can move the slider to check the animation area.
To check the animation area,
how many frames are there?
You can manually enter it here.
For example, I want to only see the animation of 0 to 200 frames.
Then I will enter it here.
Then in my vision, I can only see 0 to 200 frames at most.
The slider is different from the change.
The slider means that the first frame is in the process of you changing the frame rate.
For example, it is 30fps.
When you turn it to 60fps,
then your second has not changed.
That is, you are still within 5 seconds.
5 seconds or 5 seconds to finish this animation.
But your frame rate is increased.
If you choose the slider,
that is, the animation of 5 seconds,
you may finish it within 2.5 seconds.
Because you have locked all the frames on the current frame.
Then the fps is exactly 60.
In addition to this setting,
we can slide the slider.
For example, when you slide the slider to the left and right ends,
then the entire panel of the animation editor
is set to 0 to 200 frames.
In fact, it is similar to other 3D software.
You can slide the slider to see the range.
This is the modification of our animation editor.
Then let's talk about the next new function.
The next new function is called the part-format optimization.
Part-format optimization,
as the name suggests,
is the part-format optimization of the clothing.
If you have not used the part-format optimization,
I will briefly introduce it to you.
The function of the part-format optimization is that
when we, for example,
make some adjustments to the clothing,
for example, I now have some wrinkles on it.
If I use the brush to brush them,
there is a part-format optimization on the right.
When I do the part-format optimization on a certain part,
even if I turn on the simulation,
the wrinkles on this part
will try to maintain its trend.
Therefore, in normal circumstances,
this piece of clothing will be
relatively vertically attached to the body.
But because I used the part-format optimization,
this part will remain in the current position.
In this way,
we can manually adjust some wrinkles
to achieve the effect we want.
And when you change the movement,
or when you record the animation,
you can do the part-format optimization on a certain part.
Then your wrinkles will be usable.
Then if you select the part-format optimization area,
you can delete them.
For example, after deleting this part-format optimization,
turn on the simulation,
it will return to normal.
You may not have a good idea of this.
I can give you a simple demonstration.
For example,
now we have a pair of pants without wrinkles.
But sometimes,
we hope that there are some wrinkles on the part-format optimization.
Then we can achieve these wrinkles
with some special movements.
For example, like pants,
we can turn on the simulation
and push its legs up a little bit.
OK.
In this case,
we can see that the part-format optimization
will cause some wrinkles
due to some compressions.
Right?
OK.
Let me decrease the strength of the pen.
Then after the formation of the wrinkles,
we can use this tool.
Let's use the brush first.
Brush the part-format optimization here.
For the self-directed model,
it is best to use Morph Target.
After selecting the wrinkles of the part-format optimization,
we can change the shape.
OK.
After changing the shape,
we can simulate it again.
Then we can change the posture of the model
to the upright posture.
The shortcut to control the wrinkles
is Shift X.
OK.
Because the area I choose is relatively large,
if you want to maintain
the effect of the entire model,
you can continue to select more
before adjusting it.
If you use your own brush,
you can select some bones
that are folded up
in other 3D software.
OK.
Then if you need to delete it,
you can delete this part-format optimization area.
Then,
if you want to simulate it for a short time,
it can maintain a certain wrinkle.
OK.
This is our part-format optimization function.
Currently,
the part-format optimization function
is not able to control the strength of the edge fusion.
But because we now
actually select the grid brush function,
it is a soft choice.
Then I believe that there may be
better applications in the future.
OK.
Next,
let's take a look at the next new feature.
The next new feature is our shop.
In Modelist Designer 11,
we have already built-in a shop.
In the upper right corner,
you can log in.
If you log in,
please note that
it is not the account of your software,
but the account of your official website
that you can log in.
After logging in,
we can see that there are a lot of products here,
right?
When we put the mouse on a product,
we can see its name,
price,
and its number of collections.
Then we can see that
some of the files
are zero-dollar purchases.
You can add them to the shopping cart
or collect them.
When you add them to the shopping cart,
you can directly pay for the purchase.
Yes,
I am now displaying the new feature of
Modelist Designer 11.
When you click on the button,
you can see that
there are a lot of products here.
This is a new feature of Modelist Designer 11,
built-in shopping cart.
Then in the upper left corner,
you can enter some names
to search.
Here is our
gender and age selection.
For example,
you can choose to only look at
men's clothes
or women's clothes.
Because after we upload
such clothes,
we will give it a label.
You can search according to your needs.
Then next to it is the style.
For the style,
you can see
how these clothes are divided.
For example,
you can choose to only look at the coat,
or only look at the underwear,
and so on.
For the purpose,
it means
when this dress was used.
This dress,
for example,
is a daily dress
or a more special
historical dress.
Then in the upper right corner,
you can choose
not to display
the clothes you already have.
You can also adjust
the way to order.
For now,
in our store,
you can try
it on Connect.
Then in this version,
in the store,
if you double click on a dress,
the details on the right side
will appear here.
It corresponds to some,
including some of its details
and its 3D check,
and so on.
Then at the top,
it is its name.
Then it is the author
of the name of the file.
Then below,
it is the type of the license.
For example,
when you buy,
you can choose the basic license,
or the extended license.
If you choose the basic license,
then this project
can only be used by you
or the company within
five employees.
If you choose the extended license,
then you need to pay
three times the price,
but you can use it
in the entire company's project.
If it is free,
then it doesn't matter.
You can go straight to the next step.
Then there is a 3D checker here.
The 3D checker
needs a certain time to open.
We can wait for it to open.
Then we look at other things first.
You can directly add this file
to the shopping cart.
Then below,
it is whether it can be used
for actual production.
Then there is the size of the file.
Yes, here we can
adjust the price from low to high.
Then we can see
those free products.
You can go to MD now
and download these free products
and use them.
OK, this is the 3D checker.
In the 3D checker,
you can preview this product,
its appearance,
and you can also see its grid.
These are all our free products.
There are many of these.
In fact,
they are some of our
MD live broadcasts.
Yes, not all the clothes are free.
Some of them need to be paid.
Then below is its label.
Free ones will not be paid.
Then below is the preview of the rendering.
Then next to it is the shopping cart.
Here is its total amount
and you can click on payment.
Then on the right side
there is my product.
Here you can see
the products you have already purchased.
Then click on download
and you can use them.
OK,
then let's finally look at
this new function,
smart top.
Currently, MD can't
sell clothes by itself,
but it should be open in the future.
Next door should have
an open upload.
You can try it.
It's called Connect.
Take a look at the website.
Because MD's merchants
are not the same as theirs.
You can sell it there,
but not necessarily here.
As far as I know,
MD merchants now need to go through
our approval standard
to be able to let you
upload.
Finally, let's talk about
this is our last
main new function,
smart top.
In Marvelous Design 11,
when we use the top tool,
there is an option
called smart top.
Here it is.
As we click on the mouse,
we can create some top faces.
OK,
our opening
is only
after the end of the talk.
When the user
finishes the talk,
the opening will take place.
After we use
the smart top,
we can connect it
to, for example,
the four sides.
After connecting the four sides,
they will automatically
form a network of top.
Let's continue to create
these top faces.
Once the four sides
or the three corners are formed,
the smart top will automatically
form a network of top.
When we select the top
that has already been formed,
we can modify
the details on it.
OK,
when we finish drawing,
click on the create button
and the top will
appear.
Then you can follow the
top that has already been formed
to proceed with
the next steps.
You can create
or delete them.
For example,
I drew a top
that has problems.
If it is not ideal enough,
click on delete
and you can delete
these unnecessary lines.
OK,
I can see
that in the process of creating
the smart top,
I still have to tell you that
whether you are doing the inside
or the outside,
along the outside of the board,
they all need to be
a four-sided
or a triangle.
They will pass.
Then click on delete
and you can delete the unnecessary ones.
OK,
did you notice that
after I created
the top,
do you see that
there are some blue dots on the right side?
The blue dot
corresponds to
the seam line
on the side of
our suit.
When there is a seam line
on the side,
once we have created
the top,
you can create the top
along the seam line.
In this way,
you can make sure that
the points on the side
are aligned
when you are drawing.
This is the tool
we have just updated
called the support top.
Thank you for your support.
Thank you.
This is the main update
about the support top.
In the latest Marvelous Designer,
if you want to
support top,
once you create
these support points on the side of the seam line,
the other side
can be automatically
absorbed.
Thank you.
The tutorial of MD combination animation
is mentioned in the previous video
and also in the last Christmas live broadcast.
This is the main new feature
of Marvelous Designer 11.
Other features
are mentioned in the previous live broadcast.
You can watch the previous live broadcast
in the previous live broadcast.
Let's move on to the next part.
The support top
can be used
as a seam line.
The support top
can be connected
to the seam line.
Let's move on to the next part.
If you have any questions,
you can answer them in the Q&A section.
Thank you for your support.
Thank you, Hua Hua.
After this part,
we will draw five
annual members,
OK?
Listen carefully.
Time flies.
We can enter
the draw section.
OK.
This is a video I recorded in advance.
The final effect
is the promotion we saw.
This is the effect
on the promotional poster we posted now.
OK.
Let's start.
This is a video
I recorded before.
I will first
bring in a suit of men's clothing.
Arrange it and wear it.
OK.
After wearing it,
because I want to make
a draw effect
with a shirt,
I will use a 3D drawing tool
to draw a line directly
on the clothing.
For example, I want to make a shirt,
I will put on a big dress
and use this 3D drawing tool
to draw a line on the dress
and cut it off.
After cutting it off,
I will select all these
panels and
start the simulation.
Before we start the simulation,
we need to draw
a line to draw a rope.
So,
I will use the 3D drawing tool
to draw a line
on two ropes.
OK.
The switch of the group tool
is not in 11.
In 11,
you can directly
cut off the
user-defined menu.
So, this tool can only be turned on
before 10.
After I
make a flexible application
for these lines,
you can see that
there will be some wooden edges naturally.
Because now the clothes are
relatively large,
if you want to make these flower edges,
you must remember that your version is
much larger.
In this way,
you can control the effect
of the elastic.
Then, for these two edges,
I will apply another elastic
with a ratio of 70.
Then, it will form a flower edge
along the chest and above.
All the folds are formed
because there are many fabrics
and the fabric is large.
Can you understand this?
After that,
I decided that
I would like to make
a tree's waist.
Because I want to make
a tree's waist,
I was thinking that
there are a lot of
pieces of thread.
If you have a very tight
tree's waist outside,
it will definitely be affected
because there are a lot of
fabrics and it is very
tight outside.
It is very easy to
make a tree's waist.
In this way,
when we look at it from the outside,
it is a structure that cannot be seen.
We will try to make it
as simple as possible.
Then,
the sleeve side is the same.
Draw a line
to draw a line.
Then, I will make a line
inside it.
Then, I will add the elastic
and draw it up.
Then, I will add a
little bit of elastic here.
Then, we will have a
fluffy top.
In fact,
the most important tool
is to draw a line
on the shoulder.
Then, we will make
the skirt.
First, I will measure
the waist of the model
with a measuring tool.
If the waist of the skirt
is too wide or too narrow,
it will be too tight.
It will affect
the following operations.
So, I usually measure
the waist of the model
and make a
similar size.
Then,
I will
reduce the
strength of the
elastic and the
thickness of the
skirt.
Then,
I will apply
a different fabric.
For me,
especially the waist of the skirt,
you must remember to use
a fabric called
Fusible Rigid
or Hardwear.
In MD,
if you have a lot of fabric,
the fabric will be too heavy.
If you don't use a
hard fabric,
your skirt will fall down easily.
So, when you make a skirt,
it is better to
freeze the waist
or adjust the elastic
to a higher level
to prevent it from
deforming.
In this way,
it won't be pulled
by the skirt
or look ugly.
In the process of making a skirt,
you can draw
some panels manually.
For example,
I want the skirt
to be slightly open,
with an A on the top.
The panels I draw must be
A-shaped.
You can change
the weight of the fabric,
but if you change
even if
the density of the fabric
is set to 0,
it won't float in the air.
It will still have
a certain weight.
In real life,
it is impossible
to have no weight
in the fabric,
so you have to change the method.
If you are making an animation,
if the character runs away
or changes the movement,
it won't work.
I am doing this
because
I want to refer to
the effect of a skirt
in real life.
There are two straps
on both sides.
When I was watching
the movie,
I noticed that
there are many elements
of the belt.
I was thinking
if I could
connect the belt
with the skirt
so that it looks
like the belt is hanging
on the skirt.
This is to fix
the position of the skirt.
If I am satisfied with
the fold of the skirt,
I will keep the belt
in this position
and tie it with two straps.
Then the effect will be OK.
During the process of making clothes,
you can use more
pins to see the effect.
The back piece is the same.
I will use pins
to see the effect
of this adjustment.
After I added
a row of pins,
I felt that
if I just pull up
a few sides,
it seems that the effect is not very good.
So I finally chose
to draw some inside lines
and a belt
to make a similar effect.
You see,
even if the skirt itself
is not very heavy,
it will also pull
the belt longer.
So we have to
modify it while doing it.
Of course,
it is necessary to
make some adjustments
during the process.
After making the belt,
I will expand the belt.
The function of expanding the belt
is that I will add a button
at this position
to make it look like
using the effect of the button
to tie the skirt
and the belt together.
There will be a screen.
Because the belt
and the structure of the skirt
will not be directly
sewed to the skirt.
So I will
convert it here
and use the button
to connect them together.
I have done the button here.
In fact,
we use the inside line
to sew it.
But after we make the button,
we can cover it here
to make it look less obvious.
And it looks like
it is fixed with a button.
Because if you just use a button,
it is not enough.
The power of the button
is not enough to support it.
The strength of the sewing line
is stronger.
Then you can
change the fabric of the skirt.
For example,
I choose the fabric of the
button here.
The feature of the button
is that it can make your skirt
feel very supported,
very puffy,
and its weight is not very high.
In fact,
it is also very simple
to deal with these wrinkles.
You can use this simulation
to drag the fabric
during the process of
making clothes.
Here,
I increase the strength
of the lining of the skirt.
After increasing the strength of the lining,
the wrinkles will be more obvious.
So if you
want the wrinkles to be more obvious
during the process of making clothes,
you can increase the strength
of the lining.
Then I will shrink it
to make it a tight style.
This is to make it easier
to wear.
Then the edge of the skirt,
because we don't know
if you still remember
that the edge of the skirt
is relatively wide.
Then you add a shrink to it,
it may not be tight.
So I will give it a negative pressure,
which is to use the pressure
to tighten this dress
on the model,
so that I can wear it outside.
For example,
if you wear it outside,
otherwise,
because we just put on the dress,
it is a relatively loose structure.
If you wear clothes outside
when you are loose,
it is difficult to wear them
stably.
So you must make the inner layer
of the clothes completely wrapped
and close to your model body,
so that it is convenient
to carry out some subsequent creation.
Then this pair of shoes,
I have taught you
in a previous video.
Because I want to make a different pair of shoes,
I will use it directly.
Then use this
measuring board tool.
When using the measuring board tool,
you can cut along a direction.
It is like a level
cutting tool.
You can cut this pair of boots.
After cutting,
for example,
I can draw a inner line along it.
Then,
I can cut this pair of boots
along the horizontal direction.
This way,
I can save some drawing time.
Then,
this pair of boots
from a high long boot
to the knee position
becomes a shorter,
medium-sized boot.
After that,
when I saw the reference of
a lot of clothes from
Zhenqi and Pengke,
I found that they really like to use
the elements of bandage,
including boots
or some laces.
When you make a bandage
in Marvelous Designer,
do you sometimes feel that
the bandage is easy to fall off
or that the bandage
is unstable?
Yes, there will be a loop.
Then,
the process of making the bandage
is definitely not
to do it manually
or other operations.
Because this kind of operation
will make our
material
very burdensome.
So we usually do
a similar effect.
That is,
we will make a fake
bandage through the hole effect.
Here,
I have drawn
some buttons for the bandage.
Because the bandage
goes through the hole.
I am drawing
those holes.
For example,
I will draw a circle inside.
In the middle of the circle,
I will make a hole.
Like this.
But in the middle,
I don't actually turn it
into a hole,
I will make a hole.
Then,
in the final process,
I will set the middle
piece of the bandage
to be 0 transparency.
In this way,
it will look like
the bandage goes through
directly.
In fact,
the bandage is sewn
on the inner line of the
middle piece of the bandage.
It is very difficult.
It is very difficult to use it
by hand.
But it is difficult to guess
how to use these tools
flexibly.
So,
it is very difficult
to wear the bandage directly.
Because if you wear
the bandage directly,
the bandage itself
is very unstable.
If you wear the bandage directly,
it will be very troublesome.
So, we will make a hole
and sew it directly
to the hole in the middle.
Then,
if you do it from the beginning
to the end,
it is also very troublesome.
So, in the end,
I will think about it.
In this way,
we can do it in groups.
For example,
we will make a hole
and sew it directly
to the hole.
Then,
we can use these tools
in a circle.
We can use this set of
bandages in a circle.
For example,
I have finished drawing
a bandage here.
Then,
I will simulate it.
this thread
I will sew above
this太 MAC
and put together
to make it
the same height.
You can think that
the point is
a obstacle to it.
All right?
The trick is
to make it
the same height
as the type of
Now we have finished one pair of shoelaces.
What you need to do next is to copy and paste, copy and paste.
For example, this is our first pair of shoelaces.
You also copy and paste the next pair of shoelaces.
There is a big gap in the middle, so don't forget.
You can sew the middle part up.
Here you can see that I have actually turned the middle into a transparent piece.
So it looks like this shoelace has really passed through.
In fact, it didn't. It didn't pass through.
Because if it passes through, it won't be stable.
Next is to make this flipped piece of board.
Then add it to the side.
You can quickly add this board to another board.
This is the side of the board.
Then draw some inner lines and fold them.
Then start the simulation.
When we have finished the simulation,
you can simulate these boards that may interact with each other.
Let's simulate it together.
Red is not a hard drawing.
It's just that in order to distinguish and see clearly this board,
I used red.
This board is made of leather.
Then after doing one side,
you can do the other side as well.
You just need to make it directly symmetrical.
Then apply a layer to it.
Then simulate it.
Have you noticed that in the process of doing it,
I basically freeze all the other boards?
This can help me make some adjustments more quickly.
And it can ensure that some of the materials that I use often
will not be affected by other operations.
So everyone must pay attention to the process of using MD yourself.
You also have to use these tools consciously to avoid some problems.
After that,
I will draw the tree's waist directly on the human body.
Because the clothing parts like the tree's waist
are relatively close to each other.
The close-up version is very difficult to draw
because the human body has a curve.
So I will choose to draw directly on the model.
This will be more convenient.
After this,
after drawing,
use the flat as panel tool
to flat all of these panels into panels.
For flat panels,
we just need to cross-cut the panels on the other side.
and then sew them up and then simulate it.
This is all a regular operation, which was actually mentioned in previous videos.
After we actually start to simulate it,
you will find that the version that is extracted looks softer,
so I will use a leather fabric to make it look a little harder,
and there is no wrinkle.
Even if you need this version to have wrinkles, it doesn't matter.
What we are doing now is a basic version.
You can create wrinkles on the outer layer of this basic version,
and then let the outer layer produce wrinkles.
If you only make one layer,
one is that its wrinkles are difficult to be manually controlled in a certain range,
and the other is that it is easy to not stick to the body.
So the layer that sticks to the body, I am more inclined to use leather
to make some basic hard version.
Then because the chest here,
it is not,
it is a model that does not stick to the body,
so I will use a sewing needle
to sew this non-stick area for it,
and then it is equivalent to pinching a piece of clothing for it.
So we can test how much space it has,
that is, how much space it will need to be shortened.
For example, like the chest here,
I often feel that the chest,
the chest of this version is very far from the body.
Then through the sewing needle,
after pinching the two points together,
if it is attached,
then do we need to dig out such a fan-shaped area in the middle?
It's not a fan-shaped area,
it's a triangular area.
Then after digging it out,
we just add a rope in the middle,
and then after looking at the simulation,
it is attached.
Yes, this is actually called a rope.
This is a professional term for clothing.
It is used to make you more suitable for the human body.
What I am now explaining to you is
how to make a set of authentic punk-style clothing.
Then at the bottom of the clothing,
you also need to add a rope,
because the length is also not right.
After adding two ropes,
this version will be divided by us in a simple way.
Okay,
and now it is more suitable for the human body.
Yes, we are a 3D software for making clothes.
Okay,
and then after the simulation,
we can use this cut down line of this mark
to make a modification to the board,
so that it looks like a natural cut.
Okay,
now I will cut the upper chest of this board
into two pieces,
and then use the round blade
to make it more round and smooth.
Okay,
and then once you have this cover,
this shell,
you can,
you can make other modifications on this base.
As for the clothes,
if you look at the white film,
you can't see where it can be used.
Later,
when the CINO boss comes,
he puts the material aside,
you will feel that it has a very good taste.
Then,
we can cut this inner line down again,
so that this board will be cut into different boards.
Okay,
now we can see that I have made some simple cuts to this dress.
Then,
we will combine this top and bottom salt board.
After combining,
it becomes a whole piece.
It's very easy.
Okay,
now we can do it.
Through some 3D drawing,
or through testing,
I want to dig out some parts,
you can make this costume
into another kind of division.
At the same time,
it is in line with the human body.
Because we can't guarantee that
every piece of clothing we make
must be in line with the human body.
Wait a moment,
I'm going to find a rendering drawing.
Because this part is actually not very difficult.
Thank you for your support.
I'm going to find a rendering drawing.
Then,
I'm going to add it here.
I'm going to add a border
and this part.
Then I am done with this piece.
After making this bamboo chest,
I am going to add it directly to the outer side of the last one.
Is it difficult to make it to the outside of the other clothes?
And our clothes inside are already very tight, right?
When you encounter such a situation, we have to change our minds.
Since the clothes inside can't get smaller, can we make the clothes outside a little bigger?
So when you encounter such a tight situation, for example, a chest coat or belt,
and you want it to fit outside of the other thing, and the object inside cannot be transformed anymore,
if you use layers directly, it may not be able to wear it very well.
Especially at the bottom of the night, pay attention to whether the clothes outside are at the bottom of the night here,
but the clothes inside are at the bottom of the night here.
Then we need to give layers outside.
For example, we want to increase the level, for example, the level to 1,
and we need to increase the shrinkage.
After you increase the shrinkage, the clothes will become larger,
and then it can be worn out very conveniently and quickly.
After wearing it out, we can immediately reduce its level to 0,
or the shrinkage returns to 100.
so that it can automatically fit outside the clothes inside.
Then we turn on the simulation and adjust them together.
Let's take a look at the rendering.
Let's look for the rendering.
This is the final rendering.
This is the result of the rendering.
The texture of the rendering is later shared with you by Mr. Sino.
He will share with you how these renderings are done,
how they are done in the Substance pattern.
Then in order to prevent me from changing the movement later,
this shoulder strap will be a little slippery,
so I will use a fake sewing needle to sew this shoulder strap on the virtual model.
No matter how many times we move or move,
it will not affect the shoulder strap.
The shoulder strap will be fixed in this position all the time.
Then, by adjusting the length of the line,
we can keep it a distance from the model.
In this way, it will not have that obvious stretch.
After it is done,
I will cut a layer out of it.
That is, I will cut a layer out of this clothing panel.
Then, I will make some changes to the shrinkage,
and then let the outer layer of the clothes have a certain fold.
That's it.
Including the outer layer,
I may change a kind of fabric for it.
For this fabric,
I may increase its fiberglass strength a little bit.
Because the higher the fiberglass strength,
the easier it is to make some fine folds.
That's it.
It is more suitable for the clothes we wear in real life.
There will be some small, fine folds on the clothes.
And the outer layer may add some,
well, it is the end of the gold,
add some shrinkage, like this.
It is also to make them fold.
Okay.
After it is done,
I will start to make the hat for it.
Then, the outer layer,
whether it is the shoulder strap or the shoulder strap,
are all the materials I used in the past.
For that set of materials,
after a while,
I can upload it to our store,
and then give it to you for free.
After a while,
you can go to the store and have a look.
Remember to come down.
This should be in the assassin set.
Okay.
Then, it is to make the hat.
To make the hat,
well,
I will make a circle first.
Because the hat is basically round.
It has a round bottom plate.
Then, on the top,
whether it is a triangle or a circle,
I will make a cut for it.
Then, I will make a circle.
Then, I will set the height of the hat,
the position of the hat.
Then, I will put this board here.
After that,
in order to prevent the hat from falling down,
we need to use a sewing tool
to sew the hat to the head of the virtual model.
Thank you for your attention.
Thank you.
After sewing it,
let's activate the top plate.
Because the hat,
we just cut it into a circle.
The hat is usually like that
bigger or more exaggerated hat.
It's usually bigger on the top.
Then, in the middle,
slowly,
it will become smaller.
So, I will make the top circle
a little bigger than the bottom hole.
After that,
I will draw the side plate.
Because I have now roughly determined
the height of the hat,
so we have to make some adjustments
to the side plate.
Let it match the structure of the hat.
Because the hat is now big and small.
The side plate of the top plate
is definitely not a rectangle.
It should have a longer edge
and a shorter T-shape.
Then, in order to make the side
to be sewn,
there is no strange point.
So, we need to adjust the side
to be a rectangle.
There are four rectangles.
Here, here, here and here.
Four.
It is close to the structure of the rectangle.
Otherwise, it will be easier
to make some strange points
when sewing.
When you make other clothes,
or hats,
try to make sure
that the side is a rectangle.
Then, turn it over.
Look,
the structure we have now,
is the top edge wider
and the bottom edge shorter?
In this case,
the top edge is sewn
on the wider side,
and the bottom edge is sewn
on the shorter side.
Then, the curve can also be
attached to the round shape.
In fact, making these curves
with curves,
one is to match
the round shape of the top plate,
and the other is to make
each side as straight as possible
and sew the top edge.
After that, there will be
an angle of 90 degrees.
Then, after sewing,
we can simulate it.
In this case,
we have the shape of a hat.
Is it black?
I don't think so.
Okay.
Then,
we can simulate it together.
After we simulate it together,
we can set the folding angle of the sewing line.
On this side,
can you see this side?
It was a relatively soft structure just now.
Then, after we set the folding angle
of the sewing line,
it becomes a straight angle here.
As long as it is set to 90 degrees.
Our software is not a clothing software.
Our software itself is for animation,
CG, and industry.
It's just a cloth calculation software.
It's just a clothing software
at the earliest.
Then, through the length of the line,
we can also adjust the position of the hat.
Then, set the folding angle.
Let this side fold up.
Now,
this hat is done.
If the length of this hat,
if you want to make it longer,
you can pull this side down.
This side is for doing the hair.
Then,
that is to increase the length,
or increase the area of the hat.
Then, use the two needle molds.
Oh.
Is the screen blurred?
Heh he.
It's okay.
Anyway, my part will end soon.
Then, with the length of the line,
Make sure that from this point to this point, the length of the seam allowance can be adjusted to their length.
For example, if you are one centimeter, you can fix it to one centimeter.
For example, after fixing it to one centimeter, is this point closer to here?
Then the sleeve of this hat will roll up.
So the seam allowance is also a tool that you will use to do some special effects in the future.
Because it can set the distance between the two points, it can ensure that, for example, if I want this edge to bend up, then I will point this point, and then point this point.
Learn to play on fairness.
Then we will modify it, we will import a model, and then we will do a ratio reduction for it.
Then modify the surface of this, this, this, and then let it have a version of the conflict.
Okay, okay, this is our part.
The part I talked about is over, and then it's time for us to move people's hearts.
Let me take a look.
Okay.
All right, you can QA for now.
Do you have any questions?
We have five minutes left to answer questions.
After we answer the question, we will start to draw the first round of draw.
It doesn't matter.
We will upload the next live video afterwards.
If you have any questions, you can just go back and view the replay.
3060, budget.
Budget reading.
If it will be stuck for a long time, you can save the project file first, and then reopen the project file, it will be a little better.
Oh, how does the hat come together?
This hat, then, is you put this point between the points, add two false stitches,
and then, and then you look at the model, they will bend together.
At this time, you set the distance they bend, which is the length of the line,
it will bend on both sides.
To do Marvelous Designer 11, wait a minute, let me pick one by one.
The fabric used for the belt is made of leather, full green leather.
And then the top is not 11.
There has been a top for a long time, but there is a better top for 11.
Why are there so many flat fabrics?
It's because in the process of drawing,
I pressed the left button too many times.
Just because you press it, it's a straight line.
MD is more of a CPU.
It's more of a GPU, but it's not that strong.
It's still a priority to look at the CPU.
Uh, if the fabric is hand-painted, you, uh,
Uh, the next door is already successful.
I think we are also very fast.
At present, if you want to use hand-painted fabric,
You have to go to our, uh, this, uh,
There was a video before.
Uh, it's physics, physics attribute settings.
That Chinese physics attribute setting.
The particle diameter can't be adjusted to the first face.
This is because when you select a version,
You only show the face of this version.
If you reduce the particle diameter to 1,
Your face will definitely go up.
The Chinese version of the entry tutorial is in our official website.
It's, it's on this Bilibili account.
0900X
It's best to use Intel's CPU.
It's, uh, AMD can do it too.
But, uh, Intel is better.
Thank you, thank you.
Uh, I don't speed up the live playback.
It's just that I rarely speed up the previous video PR.
That demo video.
If you copy a piece of it,
It's because you didn't choose merge when you copied it.
You have to choose the merge point.
Or you don't want to choose that.
Um, more projects.
You choose one.
Uh, the particle diameter of the clothes.
In fact, the particle diameter is the same as what I said before.
Uh, it's a, it's a relatively broad concept.
You can make the particle diameter a little smaller than the smaller version.
You can make the larger version a little bigger.
Or something like that.
It's just that there's no foldable version.
You can make the particle diameter, for example, 20.
Or the inner layer of the clothes.
You just make the particle diameter a little bigger.
For example, like those underwear, T-shirts.
You can make the particle diameter 20.
Only in a specific part.
You brush it with a brush.
Then use that part of the grid to divide it.
That's it.
Uh, there is a fabric preview in the group.
You can go into ZB to make a pattern.
Right.
Then, after downloading the software.
Basically, you don't need to set anything.
You, uh, just install it.
Then you can choose the Chinese setting.
The value of the particle direction.
Is to control the shape and shape of the fabric.
That is to say.
A fabric, for example.
Open the software.
For example, there is an edit particle diameter.
In fact, this direction is that.
The value of the particle direction.
Like now, it's 0 degrees.
Uh, this is 90 degrees.
Just turn it over.
That's because the fabric is.
The physical properties of our fabric.
It's divided by that.
Gold, gold, sand, tail, sand.
Just follow this arrow.
The direction is gold.
And then it's 90 degrees.
It's the tail.
Hello, hello.
Hello.
Right.
The fabric that is not easy to transform.
It's also leather.
Uh, it's still leather.
Will this tutorial case come out?
Um, it shouldn't.
Because this is a special set.
It's a anniversary.
Uh, it's not a anniversary.
It's the user exchange conference.
Will be released.
Uh, the distance adjustment between clothing and the human body.
It's best.
Just one is 0.
One is 1.
It's better to be added together.
1 is better.
ABC格式
It's not Google.
Um.
The one with the down jacket.
There is one called.
Silk.
Uh, it's called.
Polished taffeta.
That one.
Hahaha.
The level is good.
Good.
Uh.
Clothes.
If there are more panels.
It's a huge card.
Some of them are anti-red.
Then you.
Just don't simulate the whole thing.
Or your panel.
Um.
Oh.
Hahaha.
What I just said.
It should be leather.
Um.
Uh.
Clothes.
If there are more panels.
It's a card.
You are.
Um.
It's your example.
Like.
I'm.
Have a look.
I'm using a little.
Hold on.
It's not.
I'm not.
This is one of my customers.
What's that?
It's your brother.
Uh.
I'm over there.
Um.
I can't see you.
There is no problem.
Yes.
Uh.
Um.
Okay.
Uh.
Well.
Um.
If you still have any questions, you can ask them in the Q&A section at the bottom left corner or at the end of the video.
Let's ask some questions. Let me have a cup of coffee.
Let's start the draw, shall we?
I got this one.
Let's draw 5 lucky children from the last 50 chats.
Let's have a chat.
Don't post 1 first.
What should we post?
Let's post, I love MD.
Is it too difficult?
Let's post MD.
MD.
Let's draw 5 lucky children from the last 50 chats.
You don't need to post I love.
I'll say 3, 2, 1, stop.
3, 2, 1, stop.
Okay, okay, okay.
That's enough.
Congratulations to these 5 lucky children.
Thank you all for the comments.
That's enough, that's enough.
Congratulations to these 5 lucky children.
I'll say 3, 2, 1, stop.
Mo Xiaoyun Shu.
Mo Liang, who is autistic.
What is this called?
Sasano.
Congratulations to these kids.
The most beautiful.
Congratulations to these 5 kids.
Congratulations to these 5 B站 users.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And then I'll...
Remember your IDs right now.
Talk to me in private later, okay?
或者礼拜二之前,或者你们加一下我们Q群,然后你找一下我,好不好?